English in 5 minutes.
Good conversation, less frustration.
Welcome to English in 5 minutes podcast.
This is Hania speaking and today I'm talking again with Chuck.
Hello Chuck.
Hello Hania.
Good to see you.
It's nice to be here.
I'm going to enjoy this today.
Hopefully.
Today we'll be talking about food.
I know that you really like cooking and can you tell me what types of food you really
like?
Cooking has been my hobby for many years but since the lockdown I was able to learn how
to make more things like egg rolls, Indian non-bread.
I really go online and anything that catches my eye.
I'll experiment.
I like to try different things.
Okay so when you search for new inspirations it's like you write something in Google like
any special word like best recipes ever or what?
I would write like with the Indian non-bread.
I wrote non-bread Indian non-bread and then there are many different kinds just like you
have the pierogi here.
You can have it with meat or with cheese or with fruit and so this is how I started.
Now with the egg rolls I tried every egg roll place here in Leggino and they were all good
and then I thought hmm they're a little bit pricey so maybe I can try to make this at home.
So I went online and I started looking for recipes but a lot of times when you try one
recipe you'll come to and like I go to a website called All Recipe and I ask for egg rolls
and then they'll show me egg rolls but they'll show me 10 other things that I didn't even
think about and I thought oh next time maybe I'll try that.
Yeah it's good to try new things and you know non-bread I last ate that I don't know a couple
of weeks ago but I bought it in Bittronka but it was pretty tasty.
But the special Indian non-bread has ground meat inside.
That's why I said it was kind of like pierogi because you can stuff it and it's flat.
Okay great.
Okay so Indian food what about Polish food because our kitchen and Polish cuisine are
very fatty and greasy you know and sometimes if you're really full after eating that.
I think that's what I love about it that's what we have in Poland.
Poland hasn't come with Texas.
Hours too.
Very sometimes very heavy very fat very greasy.
For example you have pierogi we have dumplings.
You have shabovii.
I know I'm saying that long.
We have pork chops.
So we have a lot of the same foods actually.
The difference is the spices because we have the influence from Mexico so we have more
Tex-Mex with peppers and things like this.
But the Polish kitchen is great.
Have you got any favorite dish?
Shabovii.
And my second is pierogi.
One I never had before that I really liked was interesting when I first had it was biggos.
Oh I know biggos.
When I first had biggos I wasn't really sure if I liked this.
But then I tried it again in a third time and I love it.
Okay great.
Any favorite dish that you like to prepare like not Polish dish but something that is
your special treatment when you have guests in your house?
I tried to do something a little bit unusual that they're not used to.
For example you don't see egg rolls.
People making egg rolls or people making non-bread.
I guess my signature dish would be I make a chicken with a white wine and cream sauce.
I make that for a lot of friends when they come to the house because that one I can do
very well.
I remember some time ago you showed me like lots of pictures of the food that you prepare.
There was like lots of these pictures.
You like to take photos to show your friends like yeah this is my new dish I prepared it
and now enjoy it and you know get inspired maybe also.
It started just as a diary for myself at the beginning of the pandemic when I started
to do these new recipes that I had never done before.
Like the first time I did the egg rolls and I thought all right I've never done the egg
rolls before.
Let me take a picture.
And then I would do the non-bread or let me take a picture.
And then I started just taking pictures in the first two months I showed no one.
Even my wife didn't know I had the pictures on the phone.
And then after a while she would come home and sometimes I forgot so I would make the
plate and take the picture and then she noticed.
And then she asked me to let me see your phone.
So I showed her the phone and she said oh you're taking all the pictures.
Long list.
I tried to take a picture of every new thing that I make or if I make an old recipe a
little bit differently.
English in five minutes.
Good conversation.
This frustration.