Welcome to English Unlocked with Dave Galpito, where language meets opportunity.
In today's episode, you'll hear an English conversation about ordering food in a fast-food restaurant.
Listen closely as we dive into this everyday scenario.
Pay attention to the phrases and expressions used.
Hi, I'd like to order a cheeseburger please.
Sure, would you like fries and a drink with that?
Yes, please.
Can I also get some ketchup on the side?
Of course, your total comes to $5.99.
Here's $10, keep the change.
Oh, thank you.
Here's your order.
Enjoy your meal.
Now, let's review some of the English phrases used in the conversation and what they mean.
First, the customer said, I'd like to order a cheeseburger please.
This is a polite way of requesting something.
I'd like is a common phrase for expressing desires or preferences.
Please is used to make the request more polite.
Next, when the cashier asked, would you like fries and a drink with that?
They were offering additional items to the customer's order.
And when the customer said, here's $10, keep the change.
They were telling the cashier to keep the extra money as a tip.
That concludes today's episode of English Unlocked with Dave Calpito.
We hope you found it helpful in learning English phrases for ordering food.
Don't forget to like, subscribe and leave a comment below with any questions or suggestions
for future topics.
Thanks for listening.